Austin Knauer

(720) 989-7563

austinknauer@alumni.colostate.edu

• Westminster, Colorado 80234

https://github.com/austin-knauer

Summary

I am a full stack developer with an expansive knowledge of modern technologies and methodologies used for building enterprise-level web applications. I have work experience as a front end developer using React to create dynamic user interfaces, and as a Javabased software engineer using Java and Spring to develop applications based on the microservices architcture.

Work **Experience**

Full Stack Java Developer, Revature/Citibank — April 2021 - Present

- Collaborated with team members using Agile/Scrum methodology to produce web applications with Java/Spring-based backends and React/Typescript-based frontends.
- Underwent rigorous training in an enterprise-focused tech stack, ultimately serving as UI Lead on the capstone project.

Front End Developer, Apex Learning — April 2021 - Present

- Developed HTML/React e-learning activities, singlehandedly transforming mockups to bug-free, production-ready applications under tight deadlines.
- Ensured web pages met WCAG 2.1 requirements for accessibility, with a focus on screen reader compatibility, keyboard operability, and accessible visual design.

Education & Certifications

Bachelor of Arts, Interdisciplinary Liberal Arts, Colorado State University — 2014-2017

Accomplishments included minors in English and History, nomination as a University Honors Scholar, and publication in the university literary journal The Greyrock Review.

Responsive Web Design Certification, freeCodeCamp — 2020

JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures Certification, freeCodeCamp — 2020 Front End Libraries Certification, freeCodeCamp — 2020

Skills

- Front-end development languages, libraries, and concepts including HTML, CSS, JavaScript through ES2017, React, Redux, jQuery, and REST APIs.
- Web Design tool including SASS, Bootstrap, CSS Flexbox, CSS Grid, and responsive & accessible design principles.
- Java-related technologies including Java 8, Spring, Spring Boot, Maven, Tomcat, JUnit, servlets, and JDBC.
- Data persistence tools including SQL, PostgreSQL, GraphQL, Hibernate, and DBeaver.
- Programming paradigms and concepts including Object Oriented, Functional, and Aspect Oriented Programming, Algorithms, and Data Structures.
- Development Lifecycle tools and methodologies including Git, Node, AWS, Webpack, Babel, AGILE, and SCRUM.